Is it better to speak or die?
Call Me by Your Name is a romance, drama film directed by Luca Guadagnino.
In the summer of 1983, a 17-year-old Elio spends his
days in his family's villa in Italy.
One day Oliver, a graduate student, arrives to assist Elio's
father, a professor of Greco-Roman culture.
Soon, Elio and Oliver discover a summer that will alter their lives forever.
Oliver, played by Armie Hammer.
Elio, played by Timothée Chalamet.
Mr. Perlman, played by Michael Stuhlbarg.
Annella, played by Amira Casar.
Marzia, played by Esther Garrel.
Chiara, played by Victoire du Bois.
Call Me by Your Name is a 2017 coming-of-age romantic
drama film directed by Luca Guadagnino.
Its screenplay, by James Ivory, who also co-produced, is
based on the 2007 novel by André Aciman.
The film is the final installment in Guadagnino's thematic "Desire"
trilogy, after I Am Love (2009) and A Bigger Splash (2015).
Set in northern Italy in 1983, Call Me by Your Name chronicles the romantic relationship between 17-year-old Elio Perlman (Timothée Chalamet) and
Oliver (Armie Hammer), a 24-year-old graduate-student assistant to Elio's father Samuel (Michael Stuhlbarg), an archaeology professor.
The film also stars Amira Casar, Esther Garrel, and Victoire Du Bois.
Development began in 2007 when producers Peter Spears and Howard
Rosenman optioned the rights to Aciman's novel.
Ivory was chosen to co-direct with Guadagnino, but stepped down in 2016.
Guadagnino joined the project as a location scout and
eventually became sole director and co-producer.
Call Me by Your Name was financed by several international companies, and its principal photography
took place mainly in the city and comune of Crema, Lombardy, in May and June 2016.
Cinematographer Sayombhu Mukdeeprom used 35 mm film, as
opposed to employing digital cinematography.
The filmmakers spent weeks decorating Villa Albergoni,
one of the main shooting locations.
Guadagnino curated the film's soundtrack, which features three
original songs by American singer-songwriter Sufjan Stevens.
Sony Pictures Classics acquired worldwide distribution rights to Call Me by Your Name
before its premiere at the 2017 Sundance Film Festival on January 22, 2017.
The film began a limited release in the United States on November 24,
2017, and went on general release on January 19, 2018.
It received widespread critical acclaim, particularly for Ivory's screenplay, Guadagnino's direction,
Mukdeeprom's cinematography, and the performances of Chalamet, Hammer, and Stuhlbarg.
The film garnered a number of accolades, including many for
its screenplay, direction, acting, and music.
It received four nominations at the 90th Academy Awards, including Best Picture and Best Actor for 22-year-old Chalamet (the third-youngest nominee
in the category), and won Best Adapted Screenplay, making Ivory the oldest winner of a competitive Academy Award in any category.
The screenplay also won at the 23rd Critics' Choice Awards, 71st British
Academy Film Awards, and the 70th Writers Guild of America Awards.
Call Me by Your Name is now considered one of the
best films of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, upper
class, italy, swimming pool, coming of age.
The tone is emotional.